Guide to the Robert M. Rosenzweig, Vice Provost of Stanford University, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert M. Rosenzweig, vice-provost of Stanford University, records
1963-1975
SC0091
Stanford University. Office of the Vice Provost.
21 Linear feet
Primarily administrative files which include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, and publications. Subjects include minority affairs at Stanford, curriculum and departmental affairs, Association of Independent California Colleges and Universities (AICCU), international studies, overseas programs, student protests on campus (1968-72), Seminar on the Role of Higher Education in National Development in Asia (held in Korea in 1968), and fundraising.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Provost's Office, 1971, 1974.
Information about Access
Requested materials must be reviewed by the university archivist before they are released to patron use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Associate Dean of the Graduate Division from 1962-1967, Robert Rosenzweig was named Associate Provost in 1967 and promoted to Vice Provost in 1971.
Description of the Collection
Primarily administrative files which include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, and publications. Subjects include minority affairs at Stanford, curriculum and departmental affairs, Association of Independent California Colleges and Universities (AICCU), international studies, overseas programs, student protests on campus (1968-72), Seminar on the Role of Higher Education in National Development in Asia (held in Korea in 1968), and fundraising.
Access Terms
Association of Independent California Colleges and Universities.; Rosenzweig, Robert M.; Stanford University. Graduate Division.; Stanford University. Office of the Provost.; Stanford University. Office of the Vice Provost.; Stanford University. Overseas Study Program.; International relations.; Minorities--Education (Higher).; Students--Political activity.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Brookings Bulletin, Undated (Box 1)
  - Succeed Committee, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Minorities--"Multi-Culture Institute" T. Francois, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Summer Program at Stanford, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee (Ravenswood) Summer Program English Dept., Undated (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee (Mexican American) Summer Program Physics Dept., Undated (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Economic Opportunities Commission of Santa Clara County, Undated (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Mexican-American Conference, Undated (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Grad School Business Scholarship Program, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Sequoia Union High Sch. District Research, Undated (Box 1)
  - Minorities Committee Request for Support, Undated (Box 1)
  - Upward Bound Programs, Undated (Box 1)
  - Upward Bound Correspondence OEO, Undated (Box 1)
  - Upward Bound Grant No. CG-7983 Rejected, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Upward Bound, Undated (Box 1)
  - Upward Bound Grant No. 7933 UB OEO, Undated (Box 1)
  - Upward Bound Project Application, 1966 Mar 1 (Box 1)
  - Djerassi Matter, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Conflicts of Interest Committee, Undated (Box 1)
  - Dr. Heffner's Research Policy Institute, Undated (Box 1)
  - Recruitment of Southern Teachers, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Political Science, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Committee on Research Policy (National Science Foundation), Undated (Box 1)
  - Committee on Research Policy Effort Reports (PHS), Undated (Box 1)
  - Stanford Center for Research and Development in Teaching Quarterly Progress Report, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Untitled Notebook, Undated (Box 1)
  - AID Correspondence, Undated (Box 2)
  - Computation Center, Undated (Box 2)
  - Computer Science, Undated (Box 2)
  - Stanford Studies in International Conflict and Integration, Undated (Box 2)
  - Notices and Bulletins Stanford University, Undated (Box 2)
  - Research at Stanford, Undated (Box 2)
  - Arye Perlberg, Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Effort Reporting, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Employment of Minorities Comm., 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Computer, Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office East Palo Alto Day Sch., TMU, 1968 Mar (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Mid-Peninsula Christian Ministry, Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office (M) New Careers Program in San Mateo County Probation Dept., Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Project of Equality of Ohio, Undated (Box 2)
  - (Min) Retraining Program for Teachers in Multi-Cultural Education, 1968 Summer (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Urban Coalition (Sanford Dornbusch), Undated (Box 2)
  - Workshop on the Negro and Higher Education, Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Mernoy Harrison, Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office California, Council for Educational Opportunity, Undated (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Comm. For Positive Forces VISTA Application, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Provost's Office Business Council for Minority Students Programs, Undated (Box 2)
  - Minority Bedford-Stuyvesant Prospectus, Undated (Box 2)
  - RMR Political Science Dept., Undated (Box 2)
  - Misc. SAITO, Kimimori (RMR Advisee), Undated (Box 2)
  - Alumni Assoc. Chicago Conference, 1969 May 22 (Box 2)
  - Stanford Alumni So. Calif. Conference, 1969 Feb 16 (Box 2)
  - RMR Committee on California, Undated (Box 2)
  - RMR Conferences, Meetings, Undated (Box 2)
  - C.R.I.S. Comm. On Atlantic Study Meeting, 1967 Spring (Box 2)
  - RMR American Council on Education Seminar, 1967 Mar 24 (Box 2)
  - RMR Executive Seminar Center, Undated (Box 2)
  - RMR National Foreign Policy Conf. for Educators, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Foreign Visitors and Students, Undated (Box 2)
  - Assn. of Grad. Sch. Comm. On Deadline Data for Appmt. Of TA's and RA's, Undated (Box 2)
  - Comm. On Financial Awards (External), Undated (Box 2)
  - Ph.D. Subcommittee Ph.D. Orals, 1967 Mar (Box 2)
  - NDFL Grad. Fellowships Comm., Undated (Box 2)
  - Comm. On Financial Awards (ex) "Fellowships for Juniors" Project, Undated (Box 2)
  - RMR Serving on Committees, Undated (Box 2)
  - NDFL Proposals, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - NDFL Russian and East European Language and Area Center, Undated (Box 2)
  - Grad, Div. Assn. of Grad. Schools, Undated (Box 2)
  - C.C.H.E. Title 1, Undated (Box 2)
  - C.C.H.E. Technical Advisory Comm. HEA Part A, 1965 (Box 2)
  - C.C.H.E. Equipment Grant Program (Title VI) Title IV, Undated (Box 2)
  - NDFL Stanford-Washington Summer Language (Legters), Undated (Box 2)
  - Comm. On Low Cost Housing, Undated (Box 3)
  - TA Comm., 1969 Feb (Box 3)
  - SES Report of Subcommittee on Special Constituencies, Undated (Box 3)
  - SES Teaching and Research Subcommittee, Undated (Box 3)
  - Committees-Comm. On Gov't of Univ. Minutes and Agendas, Undated (Box 3)
  - Committees-Comm. On Gov't of Univ. Reports and Memos, Undated (Box 3)
  - SES Committee Reports, Undated (Box 3)
  - SES Sub. Admin. Structures, Undated (Box 3)
  - SES Admissions and Financial Aids, Undated (Box 3)
  - Committees SES Admissions Committee Report, Undated (Box 3)
  - SES Subcommittee on Special Constituencies, Undated (Box 3)
  - Comm. On Parking Problems, Undated (Box 3)
  - David Jacks Search Comm., Undated (Box 3)
  - Comm. On Graduate Division, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Student Financial Aid, 1968 Apr 4 (Box 3)
  - Ad Hoc Senate Comm. On Relations with Student Gov't, Undated (Box 3)
  - RMR Scott, Foresman, Inc. Social Studies, Undated (Box 3)
  - RMR Scott, Foresman, Inc. 5th grade Inter-Am. S.S., Undated (Box 3)
  - RMR Scott, Foresman, Inc. Atlantic Inst. Material (5th grade book), Undated (Box 3)
  - RMR Scott, Foresman, Inc. 3rd grade Social Studies, Undated (Box 3)
  - Visiting Committees Monthly Budget Sheets, Undated (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Committee of Fifteen, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Gov't Relations Committee-Committees, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Gov't Relations Committee-H.L. Packer, Undated (Box 4)
  - Housing Advisory, Ad Hoc Committees Minutes, Undated (Box 4)
  - Housing-Concerned Local Organizations, Undated (Box 4)
  - Housing Advisory, Ad Hoc Committees, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Human Biology, Administration of (includes proposal and grant), Undated (Box 4)
  - Human Biology - minutes of the Committee, Undated (Box 4)
  - Human Subjects-Committees, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Man and His Environment Program, 1969 Fall (Box 4)
  - E. Minert, Undated (Box 4)
  - PATU-Tent City, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Research and Development in Teaching, Center for, 1968 (Box 4)
  - San Mateo County Human Relations Comm/Program (Mary Zucher), Undated (Box 4)
  - Terman Faculty Plan, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Stanton, Robert (Harry Camp Fund), Undated (Box 4)
  - Inter-Univ. Correspondence Virgil K. Whitaker, Undated (Box 4)
  - Misc. Educ. Relations with Eastern Europe, Undated (Box 4)
  - Misc. Comm. On Governmental Relations-Comm. On University Policy (COUP), Undated (Box 4)
  - National Educ. Improvement Act, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Proposal Summary, 1966 Aug 26 (Box 4)
  - AID Grad. Sch. Of Business/Peru (AID/la-103), Undated (Box 4)
  - AID Negotiations between Stanford/Bariloche, Argentina (AID/la-184), Undated (Box 4)
  - Comm. On Research Policy (National Inst. Of Health), Undated (Box 4)
  - NIH Fellowships "Human Subjects", Undated (Box 4)
  - Comm. On Science and Astronautics, Undated (Box 4)
  - Provost's Office "Since April 11" Progress Report, 1968 Nov 15 (Box 5)
  - Lyman's Statements, 1968 Nov 15 (Box 5)
  - East Palo Alto Day School. Univ. Committee-Minorities, Undated (Box 5)
  - Palo Alto Corporation, Undated (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Palo Alto Minority Problems, Undated (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Minorities, Other Programs, Undated (Box 5)
  - Political Science Minorities Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Y.O.P. Minorities Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Law School Special Minority Group Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Medical School Minority Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Grad. School of Business Minority Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Engineering School Minority Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Electrical Engineering Minority Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Junior Colleges Program. Merrill Trust Program., Undated (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Junior Colleges Program (Rockefeller Proposal), Undated (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Government Programs for Minorities, Undated (Box 5)
  - Bay Area Recruitment Minorities Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Programs, General, Undated (Box 5)
  - Athletic Program-Minorities, Undated (Box 5)
  - Underraduate Spec. 1700-Lieberman Study, Undated (Box 5)
  - Minorities, General, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Minorities, General, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Students, Undated (Box 5)
  - Koff, Undated (Box 5)
  - Nogales, Luis, Minorities, Mexican-American, 1969 (Box 5)
  - BSU Demands, 1969 Feb 4 (Box 5)
  - Employment Minorities Committee, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Mexican-American Search, Undated (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office Mexican-American, Undated (Box 5)
  - Bay Area Minority Recruitment (possible Ford Funding), Undated (Box 5)
  - Admissions, Minority Admissions, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Admissions, Undergraduate Minorities, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Tutoring Minorities Program, Undated (Box 5)
  - Black Drama Expenses, Undated (Box 5)
  - Visiting Black Scholars Minorities, Undated (Box 5)
  - Martin Luther King Fund, Undated (Box 5)
  - Government Minorities fundraising, Undated (Box 5)
  - Minorities Employment Comm. (RWL), Undated (Box 5)
  - Provost's Office News Items (Minority Affairs), Undated (Box 5)
  - Minorities-Inquiries, Undated (Box 5)
  - Civil Rights Act '64 Title VI Minorities, General, 1960s (Box 5)
  - Articles and Reprints Minorities, General, Undated (Box 5)
  - Afro-American Library Minorities, General, Undated (Box 5)
  - Minorities, General, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
  - Alumni meetings, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Academic Affairs, 1967-1971 (Box 6)
  - Academic Council, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Accreditation, 1973 (Box 6)
  - American Council on Education, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Daniels, Jack, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Pete Clecak, American Council on Education Intern, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Cohen, Kathleen, ACE Intern, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - American Council on Education Fellows-General Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Administrative Searches Here/Other, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - American Council on Education, 1969-1973 (Box 6)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Action, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Action Research Liaison Office, 1973 (Box 6)
  - AICCU MTG, Harvey Mudd College, Claremont, 1973 Sep 20 (Box 6)
  - AICCU, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - AICCU Meeting, Sacramento, Robert M. Rosenzweig, 1974 Feb 28 (Box 6)
  - AICCU Meeting, 1973 Jul 23 (Box 6)
  - AICCU, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - AICCU Committee on Master Plan, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - AICCU General, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - AICCU Executive Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - AICCU Executive Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - AICCU State Aid to Higher Education, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
  - Stanford Aliyah, 1973 (Box 6)
  - A.S.S.U., 1967-1970 (Box 6)
  - American Studies at Stanford, 1974 (Box 6)
  - American University, 1974 (Box 6)
  - ASSU/Council of Presidents, 1973 (Box 6)
  - ASSU, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
  - ASSU, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Association for the Advancement of Science, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Athletic, Freshman Eligibility, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Bechtel International Center, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
  - Berlin Historical Commission, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
  - Biophysics, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Boys' Town Center for the Study of Youth Development, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Bradley Bill, SB 818, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Budget Discussions, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Budget Policy Advisory Group, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Space, 1967-1972 (Box 7)
  - Business School, 1965-1973 (Box 7)
  - California State Constitution Revision, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Campaign, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Campaign, Major Fund Raising, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Stanford Campus Homeowners Association, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Campus Planning-Land Development, Building and Grounds, 1969-1972 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1969-1972 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Commission, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Center for Interdisciplinary Research, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Chicano Law Student Association, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Child Care Center, 1971 Jul-1972 Jul (Box 7)
  - Childhood and Society Proposal, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Children's Center, Day Care Center, 1970 Sep-1971 Mar (Box 7)
  - Children's Center, Day Care Center, 1969 Sep-1970 Mar (Box 7)
  - Children's Center, Day Care Center, 1970 Apr-1970 Aug (Box 7)
  - Clubhouse, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Committees, General-Interns, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Committees, 1973 (Box 7)
  - CoC Task Force on "Community Self-Discipline", 1970 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Education and Employment of Women, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Faculty and Staff Affairs, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Committee of Fifteen, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Computation Center, 1968-1971 (Box 7)
  - Government Policy Group, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Graduate Studies, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Committee on International Relations, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Student Services (COSS), 1971-1972 (Box 7)
  - Communications-Institute for Communication Research, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Corporate Donors, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Council for International Exchange of Scholars (formerly Com. On International Exchange of Persons), 1974 (Box 7)
  - Day Care, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Dickinson, Fairleigh S., 1970-1974 (Box 7)
  - DOD Research, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Draft-Selective Service, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Drug Abuse Center, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Earth Science-Curriculum, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Emergency Committee for Full Funding, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Engineering-Advisory Council, 1974 (Box 7)
  - English as a Second Language, 1972 (Box 7)
  - ESAN, 1973 (Box 7)
  - E.P.A, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Escondido Village, 1968-1973 (Box 7)
  - Exchange Programs, DAAD, Summer Institutes (Grad. Div.), 1971 (Box 7)
  - Exchange Programs, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
  - Foreign Scholars, 1974 (Box 7)
  - French and Italian, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Freshman Seminar Program, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Fulbright-Hays Awards, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Fundraising objectives and priorities, 1968-1974 (Box 7)
  - German exchange program, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Division-Ford Foundation Humanities and Social Sciences Grant, 1967-1969 (Box 7)
  - Graduate Support Funds, 1969-1971 (Box 7)
  - Harvard College, Bd. Of Overseers, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Hebert Amendment, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Health Officer and Bulletins, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
  - Hoover 100th Birthday Celebration, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Hoover-Soviet Material, 1972 (Box 7)
  - I.D. Cards (Student Body Cards), New, 1970-1971 (Box 7)
  - Immigration, 1974 (Box 7)
  - India, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Indirect Costs (Computing), 1973 (Box 7)
  - Information Gathering, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Insurance, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Job Opportunity Fair, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Lake Lagunita, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Leave-Junior Faculty Leave Program, Faculty Development Program, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - General: Leverhulme Trust, 1968-1972 (Box 7)
  - Lilly Endowment, Inc., 1974 (Box 7)
  - Minority Affairs: Ad Hoc Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Nairobi College, 1973 (Box 7)
  - RMR's NCERD Reader Group, 1972 (Box 7)
  - National Defense Education Act, Title VI (NDEA VI), 1970-1974 (Box 7)
  - New York City Urban Fellowship Program, 1969-1970 (Box 7)
  - Ombudsman, 1969-1974 (Box 7)
  - Overseas Study Program in Jerusalem, ad hoc Study Group concerning, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Patents, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
  - Peace Corps-Career Information Service, 1964-1967 (Box 8)
  - Pennsylvania, University of, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Political and Economic Studies in Education, Committees, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Political Science Department, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Political Science Department, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Political Science Department, 1971-1974 (Box 8)
  - Political Union, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Population Studies at Stanford, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Postdoctoral Fellowships, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Promotions and appointments, 1968-1971 (Box 8)
  - Provost Staff for Development (Green Folder Group), 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Public Affairs, the University's Role (Bonnen Study), 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - R and D Building (Research and Development), 1968-1972 (Box 8)
  - Racism and Prejudice - U.S. 170, 1967-1969 (Box 8)
  - Research Administration, 1970-1973 (Box 8)
  - Research Development Fund, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Research and Development in Teaching, Center for, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Research and Teaching Assistants, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Reunions, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Riots: Anti-Riot Legislation, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Russia: Russians-Relationship with Stanford, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - SLA-Symbionese Libertation Army, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Slavic Studies, Dept. of, 1970-1973 (Box 8)
  - Social Policy-Undergrad Programs, Committees, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Sponsored Projects Office, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Staff Training Assistance Program, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, U.S. Department of State, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Students-Tom Grissom, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Student Appointment and Discipline, 1969-1972 (Box 8)
  - Study of Education at Stanford, Packer Study, 1967 (Box 8)
  - S.E.S. (Study of Education at Stanford), 1969 (Box 8)
  - Study of Student Services - Rosenzweig, Cummings, Grube, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - S.W.O.P.S.I., 1970-1973 (Box 8)
  - Taipei "Apprehension", 1971 (Box 8)
  - Travel Policy, 1970-1974 (Box 8)
  - U.S. Department of Defense, 1973 (Box 8)
  - United Nations - University, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - University Manager, 1974 (Box 8)
  - University Research Institute to Serve Bay Area Needs, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Urban Coalition, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - Urban Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Values, Technology and Society, 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - VISTA-Office of Economic Opportunity, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
  - Visit of Yutaka Katayama and Reid R. Briggs, 1973 Sep 20 (Box 8)
  - Dr. Schulte, Director, DAAD, visits Stanford, 1973 Sep 13 (Box 8)
  - Mr. George Mizota's visit to Stanford, 1973 Nov (Box 8)
  - Abba Eban visit, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Baker, Theodore S., Visitor-seeing for Lyman, 1970 Sep (Box 8)
  - Milovan Djilas (Yugoslavia), Visiting Scholar, 1966-1968 (Box 8)
  - Visiting Scholars, 1963-1971 (Box 8)
  - Visitors, 1965-1974 (Box 8)
  - Volunteers in Asia Program, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Wage and Salary Policy and misc., 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Andres Bello Chair (Venezuelan Studies), 1969-1972 (Box 8)
  - Andres Bello Chair (Maps from Dr. Francisco Kerdel-Vegas), Undated (Box 9)
  - Yugoslavia-Programs, 1967-1972 (Box 9)
  - Disruption, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Angela Davis, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Dr. Jose Aguilar, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Newspaper Articles on Franklin, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Contempt cases of the SJC Hearing; Disruption of Lodge's speech, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Franklin Hearing, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Professor H. Bruce Franklin, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Franklin Disruptions, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Hospital Disruptions, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Grievance Procedures for hospital disruption, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Dismissals due from hospital disruption, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Franklin-SWOPSI, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Henry Cabot Lodge Disruption, 1971 (Box 9)
  - John Keilch, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Injunction-Intervention relating to Lodge disruption, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Disruptions: County and Local Assistance, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Disruptions: Faculty action and responses, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Vietnam Moratorium, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Disruptions - General, academic year, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Disruptions - General, academic year, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Disruption Propaganda, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Disruptions: S.U. News Service, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Alumni responses to disruptions, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - On closing the university, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Night Duty Watchers: Re Disruption, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Presidential Rules re: Disciplinary actions, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Identification during disruptions, 1969 (Box 9)
  - I.S.G. (Interim Study Group) - Committee for Study of Violence on Campus, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Legalities (includes Notice of Preliminary Injunctions), 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Sit-in, 1968 Spring (Box 9)
  - AEL Sit-in; Encina Sit-in, 1969 Apr-May (Box 9)
  - Disruptions - General, academic year, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - SDS Convention, 1969 (Box 9)
  - McClellan Committee Subpoena, 1969 (Box 9)
  - The New Left Project, Independent Left Radicals at Stanford, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Publications on Disruption, Miscellaneous, Academic Year, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Publications on Disruption by other schools, Academic Year, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Publications on Disruption, Miscellaneous, Academic Year, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Publications on Disruption, Miscellaneous, Academic Year, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Publications on Disruption by other schools, Academic Year, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Publications on Disruption by other schools, Academic Year, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Radical Caucus, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - S.C.I.P. (Student Committee for Involvement in Politics), 1970 (Box 9)
  - Disruptions - Statements and Declarations (includes Ehrlich/Pitzer exchange), 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - News Articles re: on-campus disruption, Academic year, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - News Articles re: on-campus disruption, Academic year, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - News Articles re: on-campus disruption, Academic year, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Statements on Police Action, 1970 Apr (Box 9)
  - Strike Activities, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Disruption Group, Committees, 1969 (Box 9)